Guide to the Mary Johnson Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Mary Johnson papers
1923-2017
MS 2050
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
14.19
(30 boxes)
The papers document the activism and political work of New Haven activist Mary Johnson. The papers consist of activist organization files, subject files, correspondence, personal papers, and protest signs and posters. Materials address peace activism, healthcare reform, living wage initiatives, support for senior citizens, government elections, constitutional rights, environmental activism, and political parties. Organizations documented include the New Haven Federation of Teachers, Local 933, Greater New Haven Coalition for People, United Farm Workers (UFW), Progressive Action Roundtable, People Against Injustice (PAI), and Livable Income for Everyone (LIFE). Materials date from 1923 to 2015, with the bulk from 1975 to 2015.
Johnson, Mary, 1922-
Arrangement
The papers are arranged in five series and one addition: I. Correspondence, 1975-2010. II. Personal and biographical files, 1923-2010. III. Activist organization files, 1969-2015. IV. Subject files, 1970-2015. V. Protest signs and posters, 1980-2012.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy of non-commercially produced items for their personal use should consult the ordering reproductions information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Mary Johnson, 2016. Gift of Joan Cavanagh, 2017.
Related Materials
Related material: Greater New Haven Coalition for People Records (MS 2007).
Biographical / Historical
Mary Johnson was born Mary Elizabeth Doherty on March 29, 1922 in Winsted, Connecticut. Her father was a telegrapher for the Associated Press and her mother worked in the classified advertising department of the New Haven Register before marrying. Johnson was the oldest of four children. As a child, Johnson lived briefly in West Haven, Connecticut before moving to New Haven when she was six years old. In 1939, Johnson started college at the New Haven State Teacher's College and graduated in 1943. She taught elementary school for six years and resigned in June 1949 in anticipation of her December 26, 1949 marriage to Carl Johnson. They had three daughters before divorcing in 1977. Mary returned to teaching as a part time substitute teacher in 1965, and was reinstated as a full time teacher at the middle school level in 1967. She taught at Troup Middle School until her retirement until 1982.
Johnson became involved with advocacy and activism groups in the late 1950s, when she became interested in anti-nuclear energy efforts. However, it was the Vietnam War that pushed her to more intensive work for the peace movement in the 1960s. She regularly went to Washington, D.C. to protest the war and was involved in New Haven-based groups including Spinsters Opposed to Nuclear Genocide (SONG). She also joined the New Haven Federation of Teachers (NHFT), Local 933 in 1967. She served on their executive board until she retired. She was one of the leaders of the teachers' strikes in 1970 and 1975, despite court injunctions barring the strikes, and she was arrested both years. Her other union work included assisting with the United Farm Workers (UFW) national organizing teams for their boycotts of grapes and wine not produced by UFW workers.
After her retirement, Johnson formed a retiree chapter of Local 933. She also supported several labor union and labor history organizations, including the Greater New Haven Central Labor Council and the Greater New Haven Labor History Association. She also founded or was heavily involved with several organizations devoted to peace activism, healthcare reform, and living wage reform. These included the New Haven Coalition Against the War, the Coalition to Stop Trident, the Progressive Action Roundtable, Livable Income For Everyone (LIFE), the Greater New Haven Coalition for People, the Middle East Crisis Committee, and People Against Injustice. Johnson died in 2017.
Scope and Contents
The papers document the activism and political work of New Haven activist Mary Johnson. The papers consist of activist organization files, subject files, correspondence, personal papers, and protest signs and posters. Activist organization files consist of newsletters, fliers, agendas, and minutes related to organizations that Mary Johnson either founded or participated with in a leadership role. These organizations focused on peace activism, organized labor, living wage initiatives, healthcare reform, and prison reform. Organizations documented include the New Haven Federation of Teachers, Local 933, Greater New Haven Coalition for People, United Farm Workers (UFW), Progressive Action Roundtable, People Against Injustice (PAI), and Livable Income for Everyone (LIFE).
Subject files include newsletters, fliers, pamphlets, and memoranda. Their materials address peace activism, healthcare reform, living wage initiatives, support for senior citizens, government elections, constitutional rights, environmental activism, and political parties. Many of the files are organized by topic. Some organizations that Johnson had an interest in but did not directly work for are included, such as the American Civil Liberties Union and Central Committee for Conscientious Objectors (CCCO).
Correspondence, personal and biographical files, and protest signs and posters comprise the remainder of the collection. They consist of personal correspondence, some organizational correspondence, awards, newspaper clippings, oral history transcripts, photographs of Johnson and her family, and signs and posters from protest and cultural events. Materials date from 1923 to 2015, with the bulk from 1975 to 2015.
Labor unions -- United States; Peace movements; Health care reform; Social justice; Johnson, Mary, 1922-; Greater New Haven Coalition for People; United Federation of Teachers
- Correspondence, 1975-2010; Series I
  Scope and Contents
  Series I mainly consists of personal correspondence. There is also material related to Johnson's imprisonment during the 1975 teachers' strike and her organizing work with the United Farm Workers (UFW).
  Arrangement
  Series I is arranged alphabetically by topic.
  - General, 1975-2010 (Box 1, Folder 1-3)
  - Prison correspondence, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - United Farm Workers (UFW), 1975-1978, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Personal and biographical files, 1923-2014; Series II
  Series II consists of papers and photographs pertaining to Johnson. The series also includes transcripts of an oral history she gave of her life, including her childhood, her time teaching, and her involvement with Local 933 and related events. Also included are additional interviews, newspaper articles, several calendars, and notes. Photographs are mostly of Johnson and her family and her 80th birthday party.
  Series II is arranged alphabetically by topic.
  - Papers
    - Award from the Haymarket People's Fund, Circa 2000 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Birthday card banner for Mary Johnson's 80th birthday celebration, 2002 (Folder 24)
    - Calendars, 1969-2010 (Box 2, Folder 2-3)
    - Certified copy of marriage license, 1949-12 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Community political activities and interests, 1972-2006 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Ed Leonard, "Dinosaurs" and "Lay Down Your Swords", 1985-1987; 1 (Box 21)
      Conditions Governing Access
      Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy of non-commercially produced items for their personal use should consult the ordering reproductions information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.
    - Essay by Nicholas Strohl: "The Origins of Organized Progressive Teacher Power within the New Haven Federation of Teachers, 1967-1972", 2004-04-05 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Interview transcript, removal of downtown New Haven bus stops, 1998-07-19 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Mary Johnson on teacher unions, 1940s-1970s, Circa 1995; 1 (Box 22)
    - Materials related to teacher's strike imprisonment, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Notes from meetings, 1974-1975 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Newspaper clippings
      - General, 1975-1999 (Box 2, Folder 10)
      - Interview with Mary Johnson, 2001-12-07 (Box 2, Folder 11)
      - New Haven teacher's strike and related events, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 12)
      - Retirement dinner for Mary Johnson's father, James Doherty, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Notes and to-do lists, 1999-2004 (Box 2, Folder 14-15, Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Oral history transcript, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 2-3)
    - Postcards and stickers, 1977-1986 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Project discussion paper on oral history interview with Mary Johnson, 1986-01 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Sacred Heart Spiritual Society certificate, 1996-03-20 (Box 3, Folder 5a)
  - Photographs
    - General, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Baby photograph, Circa 1923 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Daughter and friends, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Mary Johnson, Circa 1939-circa 1940 (Box 3, Folder 9-10)
    - Mary Johnson's 80th birthday celebration, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 11-12)
    - Pete Seeger, Circa 1980-circa 2014 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Activist organization files, 1969-2015; Series III
  Series III consists of materials from organizations that Johnson was either an active participant in or a founder of. These organizations focus on organized labor, anti-war and peace activism, living wage initiatives, healthcare, and prison reform. The materials document daily business within the organizations, with a few specific campaigns pertaining to healthcare reform, bus stop locations, and financial security for low-income families. Materials include newsletters, minutes, agendas, pamphlets, fliers, newsclippings, and photographs.
  Series III is arranged alphabetically by organization name and alphabetically therein.
  - General, 1993-2008 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - American Federation of Teachers (AFT)
    - General, 1982-2003 (Box 4, Folder 2-4)
    - Connecticut American Federation of Labor and Congress of Industrial Organizations (AFL-CIO), 1980-1989 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Federal education budget campaign, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Association of Retired Teachers, Connecticut, 1969-2003 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Central Labor Council
    - General, 1980-2001 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Articles and publications, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Minutes of meetings, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Photograph of Central Labor Council President, copy of Central Labor Council newsletter, 1974-05; 1988-12-05 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Community Works of Connecticut (CWC) agreement, 2005-2010 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Connecticut State Federation of Teachers (CSFT)
    - Campaigns, 1972-2002 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Retiree issues, 1986-1993 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Greater New Haven Coalition for People
    - General, 2012-2015 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Annual meetings, 2002-2011 (Box 4, Folder 16-18)
    - Annual reports and meetings, 1988-2014 (Box 5, Folder 1-3)
    - Bus stop campaign, 1995-2003 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Bus stop, May 3rd, Hamden, Circa 1995-circa 2003; 1 (Box 23)
    - By-laws, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Event, Salt of the Earth film screening, Circa 2013 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Health care campaign, 2000-2001 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Legislative actions, 2014 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Meetings, 2015 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Member address labels, Circa 1981 - Circa 2014 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Member information, 2012-2013 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Membership and phone lists, Circa 1981-circa 2014 (Box 5, Folder 12-13)
    - Notes, Circa 1981 - Circa 2015 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Petitions - single payer, Circa 1993 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Resources
      - General, 2012-2015 (Box 5, Folder 16-17)
      - Alliance for Retired Americans, 2015 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Greater New Haven Labor History Association
    - General, 2014 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Agenda, proposals, and minutes, 1990-2014 (Box 5, Folder 20, Box 6, Folder 1-2)
    - Donor's list, 2011 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - News and fliers, 1990-2012 (Box 6, Folder 4-5)
    - Newsletter, 1990-2015 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Notes, 2011 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Livable Income for Everyone (LIFE)
    - General, 1990-1995 (Box 6, Folder 8-9)
    - Low income credit union, 1992-1993 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Minutes and agendas, 1990-1996 (Box 7, Folder 1-2)
    - Newsletters, fliers, and brochures, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Personnel recruitment, 1993-1995 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Resources and articles, 1989-1996 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Worker ownership, 1991-1994 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - New Haven Federation of Teachers (NHFT)
    - General, 1970-2004 (Box 7, Folder 7-9)
    - Fliers and articles, 1975-2003 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Contract negotiations, 1979-1980 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Labor community report, 1984-1989 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - 1975 strike
      - General, 1975; 2005 (Box 8, Folder 2)
      - Organizing materials, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Right to strike statement, Circa 1970 - Circa 1989 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Teacher's caucus and teacher lists, 1971-1980 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Retirees, 1995-2006 (Box 8, Folder 6-9)
    - Struggle for membership and Connecticut State Federation of Teachers retirement issues, 1985-1995 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - People Against Injustice (PAI)
    - General
      - 1984-2003 (Box 8, Folder 11-18)
      - 2004-2014 (Box 9, Folder 1-11)
    - Agendas, 2011 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Agendas and minutes, 2008-2015 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Annual meeting, 2011 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - By-laws, 2006 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Civilian Review Board, 2007 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - George Gould, Gerry O'Donnell, Ronald Taylor, 2011-2015 (Box 9, Folder 17, Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Legislative proposal regarding Department of Corrections Advisory Committee, 2007-2011 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Logo, Circa 1998 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Newspaper clippings, 2011-2015 (Box 10, Folder 4-5)
    - Prisons, including forms, 2005-2013 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Progressive Action Roundtable
    - Agendas, minutes, and planning notes, 1995-2006 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Newsletter, 2005-2012 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Spinsters Opposed to Nuclear Genocide (SONG), 1985-1986 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - United Farm Workers
    - General, 1972-2010 (Box 10, Folder 10, Box 11, Folder 1-2)
    - Correspondence, 2010 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1975-1980 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Union publications and organizing materials, 1975-1980 (Box 11, Folder 5)
- Subject files, 1970-2015; Series IV
  This series includes fliers, pamphlets, notes, correspondence, and newsletters related to specific topics or organizations of interest to Johnson and often involve local New Haven events. For organizations that Johnson actively participated in, please see Series III.
  Series IV is arranged alphabetically.
  - General, 1981 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Action/arrestees, 1991-01-17 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Air, food, and water
    - General, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Anti-hunger, Circa 2015 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Environmental Equality Conference, 1992-1994 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Environmental issues, 1985-2000 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - School Nutrition, 2003-01-24 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Air traffic controllers, 1981 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - American Civil Liberties Union, 2003 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Anti-war statements, 2001 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Anti-war work, 1987-2005 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Artists, 1999 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Banking, credit unions, 1995-1998 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Benefits check-up, Agency on Aging, 2001 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Black history - photocopies from For the People: Black Socialists in the United States, Africa and the Caribbean, Circa 1987 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Boycotts, 1979-1980 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Bush Campaign, 2004 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Cancer, 1993 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Cartoons, 1979-1991 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Center for Community Change, 1994-2003 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Central Committee for Conscientious Objectors (CCCO), 1977-2002 (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Christian Community Action, 2001-2004 (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Citizen Soldier, Circa 1996 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Civil liberties issues, Circa 2003 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Coalition Against War in the Gulf, 1993-1994 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Coalition for Justice in El Savador, 1981-1989 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Coalition of Labor Union Women, 1990-2003 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Connecticut Center for a New Economy (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Connecticut Civil Liberties Union, 1994-1997 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Connecticut Climate Coalition, 2003 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Connecticut Conference for Human and Planetary Health, 1994 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Connecticut Defense Dependency, 1980-1982 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Connecticut Health Foundation: annual report, 2002 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Connecticut history, 1982-1989 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Connecticut Peace Coalition, 2003-2004 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Court cases, 1986-1989 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Death penalty, 1995-2001 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Declaration of Independence and Bill of Rights, 1993-2002 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Disabilities
    - General, Circa 1992 - 2002 (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Developmentally disabled, 2002 (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Disability rights, Circa 1991 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Don't Waste Connecticut, 1992-1993 (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - The Draft, 1980 (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Dwight Hall, 1999-2000 (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - East Timor, 1980-1981 (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - Economic sanctions, 1999 (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - Education articles, 1993-2006 (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - Farm labor, 1975-1981 (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - Federal Bureau of Investigation, 1987 (Box 13, Folder 27)
  - Fliers and pamphlets, 2001-2009 (Box 13, Folder 28)
  - Forming a PAC and Getting the Reports Right, 2003-07-31 (Box 13, Folder 29)
  - Freedom of Information Act, Connecticut, Circa 1994 (Box 13, Folder 30)
  - Genocide, 2004-2005 (Box 13, Folder 31)
  - Government
    - Campaign finance reform, 1996-01-13 (Box 13, Folder 32)
    - Connecticut legislative guide, 1975, 2002 (Box 13, Folder 33)
    - Federal and state elected officials, 1995-2003 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Primaries, 1982 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Voting, 1994-2004 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Haigh and Joan Cavanagh (Siobhan Caomanach), 1981 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Haiti, 1993-1995 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Health fair, 2004-2005 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Healthcare, 1995-2009 (Box 14, Folder 7-11)
  - Healthcare articles, 1989 - Circa 2006 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Healthcare pamphlets, 1998-2004 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Hodel, Paul, 2000 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Housing
    - Association of Community Organizations for Reform Now (ACORN), 2003-10 (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Connecticut Fair Housing Center, 2001 (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Homeless, 1999 (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - July 14 Housing Action Committee, 1989 (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - Medical liens - Connecticut Housing Center for a New Economy, 2003 (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - New Haven housing, 2001 (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - New Haven Utilities Coalition, 1978 (Box 14, Folder 21)
    - Red lining, 2003 (Box 14, Folder 22)
    - Rental assistance, 1997 (Box 14, Folder 23)
    - Rental assistance program, 1996 (Box 14, Folder 24)
    - Reverse mortgages, Undated (Box 14, Folder 25)
  - Humor, 1998-2003 (Box 14, Folder 26)
  - Immigrant issues, Circa 1994 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - "In Search of Security", 1994 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Information - articles, etcetera, 2012-2015 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Iraq, 1975-2006 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Jobs
    - Boston and Chicago, 1983-1985 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - JOBS NOW, 1983-2002 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Pension and medicare, 2003 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Wages, 1998-2004 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Jokes and satire, 2001 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Jury duty, 1987 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Justice - world hunger, Milada Marsalka, 1986 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Ku Klux Klan, 1987-1989 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Labor, 1979-2004 (Box 15, Folder 13-14)
  - Labor actions, 1997 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Labor Day Parade, 1987 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Labor on war, 2003 (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Leaflets, 1978-2002 (Box 15, Folder 18-21, Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Legal assistance for seniors, 2004 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Legislative materials, 1973 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Long Wharf Mall, 1998-2000 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Lowe's, 2004 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Mailing list, 1986-1987 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - May Day celebration, 1994-2003 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - May Day programs, 1992-2015 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Media, 1990 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Medical, 1994-2005 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Medicare, 2004-2005 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Middle East, 1981-2004 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Middle East Crisis Committee, 1994-2002 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Militarism: black communities and registration, 1984-1990 (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Military, 2005-2006 (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Mothers for Justice, 2001-2003 (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Municipal electoral workshop, 2003-07-31 (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - New Haven, 1975-2003 (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - New Haven Board of Alders, 1998-2007 (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - Newspaper clippings, 2001-2005 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Niantic Women's Prison, 1970 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Nuclear power and weapons, 1980-2010 (Box 17, Folder 3-4)
  - Oil co-operative, Circa 1977 - 2001 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Olin strike, 1979-1980 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Patriot Act, 1998-2003 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Peace and Justice, News and Views, 1999-2001 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Peace Center, 1982 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - People's Center, 2002-07-20 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Peru, 1992-1993 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Petition regarding Grenada, 1983 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Plant, Warren, 1979-1987 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Political parties
    - Communist Party, New Haven, Joelle Fishman, 1980-1982 (Box 17, Folder 14)
    - Green Party, 1992-2002 (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - Kucinich, Dennis, 2003-2004 (Box 17, Folder 16)
    - Labor Party, 1999 (Box 17, Folder 17)
    - Nader, Ralph, 2000-2002 (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - Political prisoners, 1978-1996 (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - Press release instructions, 2002 (Box 17, Folder 20)
  - Racism, 1994-11 (Box 17, Folder 21)
  - Salt of the Earth, 1953-2004 (Box 17, Folder 22)
  - Share the Wealth Project, 1995 (Box 17, Folder 23)
  - Social Security, 2005 (Box 17, Folder 24)
  - Songs and chants, 1987 - Circa 2004 (Box 17, Folder 25)
  - South Africa (Del Monte Boycott), 1977 (Box 17, Folder 26)
  - South Africa Action Committee, 1987-1989 (Box 17, Folder 27)
  - Stonecutters, 1988 (Box 17, Folder 28)
  - Strike support, 1981 (Box 17, Folder 29)
  - The Struggle, 2001-2006 (Box 17, Folder 30)
  - Take Back Our Rights, 2006-10-07 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Taxes, 1985-2004 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - To be printed, Circa 1996 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - "Together as One for Peace, Equality, and Worker's Justice" reception, 2007-12-02 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Toys, 1992-1997 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Unemployment, Circa 1966-Circa 1977 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Union organizing - Winchester, 1988-04-25 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Unions, Circa 1981 - 2003 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - United Nations petition materials, victims of police abuse, 2002 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - United Seniors in Action (USA), 1999 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - United States-Cuban relations, 1994-04-23 (Box 18, Folder 11)